Hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise number 81.
And this exercise, we will continue making our data structure in Java.
So we will create a tree traversal program that that allow us to make in order traversal, pre-order
traversal and post order traversal.
We have seen in the previous video how to make it in see.
And now we are going to make a real program that works fine in Java.
So let's make that a class called binary tree by net the three.
OK.
And for this, I will make a subclass here called nodes.
I told you in the previous video that we need a node that contains the item that contains a reference
to the left and to the right.
OK.
So create the basic nodes, the basic structure of the tree.
Is it?
No, that contains an item, a left and right point?
OK, now let's create the constructor of this class node in key and item.
We initialized, I think, equal to the key and left equal to ride equal to or not.
OK.
When you create any node, then put left and right equal to none and get that item equal to the best
key in the parameters.
Now let's create.
A note here, no object object called root.
OK.
Creating the root of the binary tree.
No binary tree, which which is the constructor of this class,
is enclosing the root equal to knock.
OK.
When you create any binary tree, then you need to create the root equal initialized the root to no.
So.
There are.
Three traversal methods that we have learned about them.
So we start by the Post or the Traverso Post posed for the traversal.
It took into the perimeter of no, no and we consider it as the road.
But we'll check if if the node equal equal to null, then return.
OK, so the post order traversal as a recap, we start by the left section.
We print the right section and we print a arrow.
So left right route.
This is left.
As I
wrote, OK.
It's very important to understand the order.
We start by post order traversal.
This is the recursion until we reach node and we pass the note to the left until we reach the node equal
to null.
So this is the stopping condition of the of the recursion.
Let's go back to the recursion section in order to learn about the mechanism behind there using recursion
and how we stop the recursion or how to control the wreckage.
OK, now we have finished from the left.
If we have a node equal equal to null, then it would return it to start back toward and printing that
left section.
Now let's see the right section.
It's very simple by passing note to the right.
You see how, when, when we use the recursion and when we understand the mechanism, how it works,
it will facilitate and make our complex world very simple.
OK.
And we need to print a road so system in order to get the route, we put system to print that out the
print node dot.
All right.
OK.
This is the route.
It's very simple.
Traversing the OK.
This is the post or traversed in order traversal, let's see void in order traversal.
We took into the perimeter the no again.
You know, it's similar to the previously one previously created method, but we need to check again.
If note equal to none, then return.
It's very similar.
But we need to make that the correct, the order that in order Attraverso, we start by left.
So we go left.
We go the route and we go, Oh, right, okay.
So in order to order, Traverso nailed to the left in order.
Traversal to the right.
This is the last section, and we need now to put the road, so I will copy this.
This is the first printing then roared and now we go in order traversal.
But this time to the right.
So you see guys left right around this printing the route because we are getting the No.
Item and right.
OK?
Now the or the traversal void
he or the traversal?
No, no.
If note is equal equal to none, then return that reversal in this order is ruled by left and right.
OK.
So with that system that allowed the current.
We put in the note that item we get then plus an item and put here
this and we call the pre or the traversal notes to their left and three or the traversal node to the
right.
Okay.
This will bring the truth.
This will print the left and this will print the right.
This will be executed many times until reaching then no equal equal to none.
This is the stopping condition of this recruitment method.
OK, now let's see how and let's test our program.
So public static
avoid Maine.
We passed drilling rigs.
We create a myth, a class object from that class binary tree called a tree.
And so this object is called three new binary three and we start by three dot root equal to one.
You know, we create it, creating the note.
So soon, you know, then you know, it should look into the perimeter.
The key?
OK.
Three the truth.
They're not equal to the.
This is the new note.
It's not the new note.
I think make no static, OK?
We have created a no as static static, let's.
OK, no.
Three, The Truth Dot left the left section of from the road would be, you know, 12th.
OK, so we have one at the top.
We have 12 to that left.
Now let's make one to the right.
So again, in order to make it right.
No, we created, you know, to the right and we pass.
No.
OK, no.
Three The truth the left dot.
OK, guys, please concentrate here.
When we have the left and the right and we need from the left of three, we need to make new notes.
We specify the left.
So 3.2.0 left and when we need to put the left of it, we also support here left equal to, you know,
and we pass like five.
OK, thank you.
Five.
Now again, with route the left the right equal to and you know what I am doing here is very simple.
We are creating at the first node here one.
We create from this is the truth.
This is the truth.
So from the road to the left, make a new node and put it inside it.
OK, you see 12 now from this route.
This is worth from this truth.
Make a right note.
And put number nine.
OK.
No, we go three.
This has left.
And this is a right go from the three.
Root, this is the tree root left and to create the left.
So you see guys load left, left, root left left, this is the left also create A..
Put it five and create from the root left at right.
Create a new node here and put it inside it.
Number six and so on.
You can create many other nodes.
And we have seen this in the lecture before.
So if we need to make a traversal in order traversal of this, it would be in order traversal.
In order.
Traversal that in order traversal tells us how to make it.
It will start by the left left left, a root right.
OK, so we start from the left section.
This is the left.
We have left this left section.
So five, five 12, it is the route six to the right.
We, we we have finished the left section.
We go through the route, which is one, and then we go to the right section which containing which
is containing nine.
And so this is then order.
We have both stored there and pre order and we have learned about them in the previous video.
So please go back to the previous videos in order to see how that we we traverse through the three,
OK?
So let's continue printing system that out that brings, and so we need to print that in order to
traversal.
We called three Dot in order to traversal and we passed the route OK.
In order to tell that we have a route for this story and that is the route that we object, that we
have specified and what we have initialized with with one at the beginning of this testing.
OK.
Again, I will put three or that this is the pre-order pre order traversal, pre-order traversal, and
this is the pause or the traversal.
Forced water traversal.
OK.
Let's run our program and see the magic.
And there we go.
We have five, 12, six, six, one and nine.
This is very, very good and it's very correct.
OK, because we have solved it in this section and these are the pre-order and the post or the traversal
that we have solved in the lectures before.
So please go back to the previous section.
Previous lessons.
In order to understand that in order pre-order and post order traversal.
And for that, we have finished the three traversal I want from you.
If you have any questions, any details, any suggestions, any answers for anything that we have discussed
or any doubt.
Please comment below.
I'm waiting your solutions.
I'm waiting.
Your suggestions.
Any recommendation to improve this course and make it very amazing.